// database questions
const quizDataAll = {
  english: [
    {
      language: "english",
      id: 0,
      tag: "beginner",
      name: "Beginner",
      quiz: [
        {
          question: "1 How do you do?",
          a: "SDASDAS",
          b: "ADSASD",
          c: "DSAD",
          d: "ALLL",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "1 Simple dimpl or Pop it?",
          a: "Simple dimpl",
          b: "no",
          c: "Pop it",
          d: "sckvirt",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "1 What is JS?",
          a: "JS",
          b: "ZALUPA",
          c: "Programming language",
          d: "Iron man",
          correct: "d",
        },
      ],
      quiz2: [
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "Ugly",
          correct: "cool",
        },
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "You",
          correct: "me",
        },
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "No",
          correct: "yes",
        },
      ],
      quiz3: [
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Hello my",
          second: "Jon!",
          correct: "name is",
        },
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Have you",
          second: "in mexico?",
          correct: "ever been",
        },
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Would you",
          second: "some coffe?",
          correct: "to drink",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      language: "english",
      id: 1,
      tag: "preIntermediate",
      name: "Pre-Intermediate",
      quiz: [
        {
          question: "1 How do you do?",
          a: "SDASDAS",
          b: "ADSASD",
          c: "DSAD",
          d: "ALLL",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "1 Simple dimpl or Pop it?",
          a: "Simple dimpl",
          b: "no",
          c: "Pop it",
          d: "sckvirt",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "1 What is JS?",
          a: "JS",
          b: "ZALUPA",
          c: "Programming language",
          d: "Iron man",
          correct: "d",
        },
      ],
      quiz2: [
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "Ugly",
          correct: "cool",
        },
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "You",
          correct: "me",
        },
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "No",
          correct: "yes",
        },
      ],
      quiz3: [
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Hello my",
          second: "Jon!",
          correct: "name is",
        },
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Have you",
          second: "in mexico?",
          correct: "ever been",
        },
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Would you",
          second: "some coffe?",
          correct: "to drink",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      language: "english",
      id: 2,
      tag: "advanced",
      name: "Advanced",
      quiz: [
        {
          question: "1 How do you do?",
          a: "SDASDAS",
          b: "ADSASD",
          c: "DSAD",
          d: "ALLL",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "1 Simple dimpl or Pop it?",
          a: "Simple dimpl",
          b: "no",
          c: "Pop it",
          d: "sckvirt",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "1 What is JS?",
          a: "JS",
          b: "ZALUPA",
          c: "Programming language",
          d: "Iron man",
          correct: "d",
        },
      ],
      quiz2: [
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "Ugly",
          correct: "cool",
        },
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "You",
          correct: "me",
        },
        {
          question: "2 Input Antonyo",
          word: "No",
          correct: "yes",
        },
      ],
      quiz3: [
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Hello my",
          second: "Jon!",
          correct: "name is",
        },
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Have you",
          second: "in mexico?",
          correct: "ever been",
        },
        {
          question: "3 Comlite this ____",
          first: "Would you",
          second: "some coffe?",
          correct: "to drink",
        },
      ],
    },
  ],
  german: [
    {
      language: "german",
      id: 0,
      tag: "beginner",
      name: "1Beginner",
      quiz: [
        {
          question: "How do you do?",
          a: "SDASDAS",
          b: "ADSASD",
          c: "DSAD",
          d: "ALLL",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "Simple dimpl or Pop it?",
          a: "Simple dimpl",
          b: "no",
          c: "Pop it",
          d: "sckvirt",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "What is JS?",
          a: "JS",
          b: "ZALUPA",
          c: "Programming language",
          d: "Iron man",
          correct: "d",
        },
      ],
      quiz2: [
        {
          question: "Input Antonyo",
          word: "Ugly",
          correct: "cool",
        },
        {
          question: "Input Antonyo",
          word: "You",
          correct: "me",
        },
        {
          question: "Input Antonyo",
          word: "No",
          correct: "yes",
        },
      ],
    },
    {
      language: "german",
      id: 1,
      tag: "preIntermediate",
      name: "1Pre-Intermediate",
      quiz: [
        {
          question: "How do you do?",
          a: "How are you?",
          b: "How you do?",
          c: "How do you do?",
          d: "Салам",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "Simple dimpl or Pop it?",
          a: "Simple dimpl",
          b: "no",
          c: "Pop it",
          d: "sckvirt",
          correct: "d",
        },
        {
          question: "What is JS?",
          a: "JS",
          b: "ZALUPA",
          c: "Programming language",
          d: "Iron man",
          correct: "d",
        },
      ],
      quiz2: [
        {
          question: "Input Antonyo",
          word: "Ugly",
          correct: "cool",
        },
        {
          question: "Input Antonyo",
          word: "You",
          correct: "me",
        },
        {
          question: "Input Antonyo",
          word: "No",
          correct: "yes",
        },
      ],
    },
  ],
};

// DOM Selectors
// const english = document.querySelector("#english");
// const german = document.querySelector("#german");
// const math = document.querySelector("#math");
const nav = document.querySelector(".nav");
const sideNav = document.querySelector(".sidenav");
const sideNavEls = document.querySelectorAll(".sidenav p");
const mainHead = document.querySelector(".main");
const main = document.querySelector(".main__inner");
const quiz = document.querySelector(".quiz-container");
const submitBtn = document.querySelector("#btn-next");
const answerEls = document.querySelectorAll(".answer");
const questionEl = document.querySelectorAll("#question");
const a_text = document.querySelector("#a_text");
const b_text = document.querySelector("#b_text");
const c_text = document.querySelector("#c_text");
const d_text = document.querySelector("#d_text");
const numOfQuestions = document.querySelectorAll("#number-of-question");
const numOfAllQuestions = document.querySelectorAll("#number-of-all-questions");

const quizInput = document.querySelector(".input-quiz");
const submitBtnInput = document.querySelector("#btn-next-quiz");
const input = document.querySelector(".input-answer");
const inputText = document.querySelector("#input-text");

const quizComplite = document.querySelector(".quiz-complite");
const compliteInput = document.querySelector(".complite-answer");
const submitBtnComplite = document.querySelector("#btn-next-complite");
const inputTextFirst = document.querySelector("#input-text-first");
const inputTextSecond = document.querySelector("#input-text-second");

window.addEventListener("load", () => {
   if (localStorage.getItem("choseed")) {
  } else {
    localStorage.setItem("choseed", "english");
  }

  let lastChose = localStorage.getItem("choseed");

  const chose = quizDataAll[lastChose];
  const temp = chose
    .map((item, index) => {
      CHOSEED = item.language;
      return `
    <div>
    <h2>${item.name}</h2>
    <div class="button">
        <button onclick="openTest(${[index]})" class="${item.tag} ${
        item.language
      }" id="btn-next">Пройти</button>
      </div>
    </div>
    `;
    })
    .join("");

  main.innerHTML = temp;
});
sideNavEls.forEach((item) => {
  item.addEventListener("click", (e) => {
    chosedQuiz = e.target.id;
    if (localStorage.getItem("choseed")) {
      localStorage.setItem("choseed", chosedQuiz);
    } else {
      localStorage.setItem("choseed");
    }
    reset();
  });
});

//SOMEDATA
let CHOSEED;
let i = 0;
let choseedQuiz;
// score of right questions
let score = 0;
// used for if();
let currentQuiz = 0;
// count of question right now
let questionNum = 1;

// our answers
let myAnswers = [];
let mySecondAnswers = [];
let myCompliteAnswers = [];

function quizLoad(road) {
  deselectAnswers();
  questionEl.forEach((item) => {
    item.innerHTML = road["quiz"][i].question;
  });

  a_text.innerHTML = road["quiz"][i].a;
  b_text.innerHTML = road["quiz"][i].b;
  c_text.innerHTML = road["quiz"][i].c;
  d_text.innerHTML = road["quiz"][i].d;

  NumOfQuestions();
}

let lengthOfQuiz;
function NumOfQuestions() {
  lengthOfQuiz =
    ourRoad["quiz"].length + ourRoad["quiz2"].length + ourRoad["quiz3"].length;

  numOfQuestions.forEach((item) => {
    item.innerHTML = questionNum;
  });
  numOfAllQuestions.forEach((item) => {
    item.innerHTML = lengthOfQuiz;
  });
}

// openTest
let ourRoad; //save choseed
function openTest(road) {
  main.classList.add("off");
  ourRoad = quizDataAll[CHOSEED][road];
  quizLoad(quizDataAll[CHOSEED][road]);
  quiz.classList.add("quiz-container-show");
}

// selection validation
function getSelected() {
  let answer = null;
  answerEls.forEach((item) => {
    if (item.checked) {
      answer = item.id;
    }
  });

  return answer;
}

// delete chose  after send
function deselectAnswers() {
  answerEls.forEach((item) => {
    item.checked = false;
  });
}

submitBtn.addEventListener("click", (e) => {
  e.preventDefault();

  const answer = getSelected();

  // quizLoad(ourRoad);
  if (answer) {
    myAnswers.push(answer);
    if (answer === ourRoad["quiz"][i].correct) {
      score++;
    }
    i++;
    currentQuiz++;
    questionNum++;
    if (currentQuiz < ourRoad["quiz"].length) {
      quizLoad(ourRoad);
    } else {
      i = 0;
      currentQuiz = 0;
      nextQuiz();
    }
  } else {
    alert("chose one of them!");
  }
});

// reload
function reset() {
  window.location.reload();
}

// open sideNav
function openSideNav() {
  nav.classList.toggle("change");
  setTimeout(() => {
    sideNav.classList.toggle("active");
  }, 200);
}

//open the new quiz
function nextQuiz() {
  quiz.classList.add("off");
  quizInput.classList.remove("off");

  nextQuizLoad();
}

let answerQuiz;
input.addEventListener("input", (e) => {
  answerQuiz = e.target.value.toLowerCase();
  answerQuiz = answerQuiz.trim();
});

submitBtnInput.addEventListener("click", () => {
  if (answerQuiz) {
    mySecondAnswers.push(answerQuiz);
    if (answerQuiz === ourRoad["quiz2"][i].correct) {
      score++;
    }
    i++;
    currentQuiz++;
    questionNum++;
    input.value = "";

    if (currentQuiz < ourRoad["quiz2"].length) {
      nextQuizLoad();
    } else {
      i = 0;
      currentQuiz = 0;
      openLastQuiz();
    }
  } else {
    alert("complite this");
  }
});

function nextQuizLoad() {
  inputText.innerHTML = ourRoad["quiz2"][i].word;
  questionEl.forEach((item) => {
    item.innerHTML = ourRoad["quiz2"][i].question;
  });
  NumOfQuestions();
}

// open last quiz

let answerQuizCompilte;
compliteInput.addEventListener("input", (e) => {
  answerQuizCompilte = e.target.value.toLowerCase();
  answerQuizCompilte = answerQuizCompilte.trim();
});

function openLastQuiz() {
  quizInput.classList.add("off");
  quizComplite.classList.remove("off");

  loadLastQuiz();
}

submitBtnComplite.addEventListener("click", () => {
  if (answerQuizCompilte) {
    myCompliteAnswers.push(answerQuizCompilte);
    if (answerQuizCompilte === ourRoad["quiz3"][i].correct) {
      score++;
    }
    i++;
    currentQuiz++;
    questionNum++;
    compliteInput.value = "";
    if (currentQuiz < ourRoad["quiz3"].length) {
      loadLastQuiz();
    } else {
      quizComplite.innerHTML = `
        <div class="quiz-over-modal">
        <div class="content">
            <h1>Хороший результат !</h1>
            <p>Ты ответил на 
                ${score} из 
                ${lengthOfQuiz} вопросов
            </p>
            <button onclick="showMeRightAnswers()" id="btn-try-again">Показать результаты</button>
        </div>
    </div>
        `;
    }
  } else {
    alert("complite this");
  }
});

function loadLastQuiz() {
  inputTextFirst.innerHTML = ourRoad["quiz3"][i].first;
  inputTextSecond.innerHTML = ourRoad["quiz3"][i].second;

  questionEl.forEach((item) => {
    item.innerHTML = ourRoad["quiz3"][i].question;
  });
  NumOfQuestions();
}

function showMeRightAnswers() {
  
  const templateFirst = quizDataAll[CHOSEED].map((item, index) => {
    return `
     <ol type="a" id="ol">
      <h1 h1>${item["quiz"][index].question}</h1>
      <li>${item["quiz"][index].a}</li>
      <li>${item["quiz"][index].b}</li>
      <li>${item["quiz"][index].c}</li>
      <li>${item["quiz"][index].d}</li>
      <h2>Правильный ответ: <span>${item["quiz"][index].correct}</span></h2>
      <h2>Вы ответили: <span style="color: #f76767">${myAnswers[index]}</span></h2>
      </ol>

      <div id="answers-tracker"></div>
    `;
  }).join("");

  const templateSecond = quizDataAll[CHOSEED].map((item, index) => {
    return `
    <ol type="a" id="ol">
    <h1>${item["quiz2"][index].question}</h1>
    <h2>Слово: <span>${item["quiz2"][index].word}</span></h2>
    <h2>Правильный ответ: <span>${item["quiz2"][index].correct}</span></h2>
    <h2>Вы ответили: <span style="color: #f76767">${mySecondAnswers[index]}</span></h2>
    </ol>

    <div id="answers-tracker"></div>
    `;
  }).join("");

  const templateLast = quizDataAll[CHOSEED].map((item, index) => {
    return `
    <ol type="a" id="ol">
    <h1>${item["quiz3"][index].question}</h1>
    <h2>Правильный ответ: <span>${item["quiz3"][index].correct}</span></h2>
    <h4>
    <span>${item["quiz3"][index].first} </span>
    <span style="color: #f76767"> ${myCompliteAnswers[index]} </span>
    <span> ${item["quiz3"][index].second} </span>
     </h4>
     <h2>Вы ответили: <span style="color: #f76767">${myCompliteAnswers[index]}</span></h2>
     </ol>

    <div id="answers-tracker"></div>
    `;
  }).join("");

  quizComplite.innerHTML = templateFirst;
  quizComplite.insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", templateSecond);
  quizComplite.insertAdjacentHTML("beforeend", templateLast);
  quizComplite.insertAdjacentHTML(
    "beforeend",
    `
    <div style="text-align: center;">
    <h2>Вы ответили на ${score} из ${lengthOfQuiz} вопросов</h2>
    <button id="btn-end" onclick="reset()">Завершить</button>
    </div>
  `
  );
}
